Dobromir Marinov

Colchester, United Kingdom

(+44) 7599-943662

mr.d.marinov@gmail.com

https://dmarinov.com/

Personal profile

I am a software engineer with 3 years of professional experience. My main programming languages are Python and Java. The research field in which I am interested is machine learning, and more specifically, reinforcement learning and machine vision. I am an EU citizen and I am eligible to work and study in the UK.

Employment

MSX International

Software Engineer (Data science department)

Colchester, United Kingdom

June 2018 - Present

- Building and maintaining machine learning models for predictive analytics in the automotive industry.
- Building microservices.
- Python, R, AWS, Docker, Nginx, Redshift, Exasol, LATEX.

MSX International

Software Developer

- Working in a team developing web applications.
- Java EE, SpringMVC, Liferay 6/7, Oracle, Jboss.
- PL/SQL, Hibernate, Freemarker, Gradle, Selenium.

Colchester, United Kingdom

November 2016 – June 2018

StangaOne1

Web Development Intern

- Developing commercial websites.
- PHP, Laravel, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery.

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

July 2016 - September 2016

Education

University of Essex

Digital and Technology Solutions (Software Engineer) (BSc)

Colchester, United Kingdom

October 2016 - Present

Capstone Project: Developing algorithm for automatic hyperparameter optimisation and neural architecture search.

Relevant Modules:

- Software Engineering.
- Data Structures and Algorithms.
- Evolutionary Computation and Generic Programming.
- Advanced Programming.

Big Data and Analytics Summer School

Delegate

- Learning Under Different Training and Testing Distributions.
- Visual recognition and tracking in large image and video datasets.
- Introduction to the Modelling and Analysis of Complex Systems.
- Artificial Intelligence and Neural Networks in Analytics.

High School of Mathematics

Secondary education

• Program with extensive study of Mathematics, English and IT.

• Graduated with excellence: 5.93 out of 6.

Colchester, United Kingdom

July 2018 - August 2018

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

September 2011 - June 2016

Colchester, United Kingdom

Colchester, United Kingdom

Colchester, United Kingdom

Certificates and awards

Award for outstanding academic achievement

University of Essex

General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

Certificate of attainment

Information Security

Certificate of attainment

The Degree Apprenticeship Prize

University of Essex

• Awarded to the 2nd year apprenticeship degree student with the best overall mark.

Colchester, United Kingdom

September 2018

June 2019

April 2019

April 2019

K.F. Bowden Memorial Prize

University of Essex

• Awarded to the top 4 first year students, in CSEE, with the best overall year mark.

Colchester, United Kingdom

September 2017

Award of Excellence

High School of Mathematics

• Awarded for overall performance above 5.80 out of 6.

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

June 2016

StangaOne1 Academy

Web Development Basics

Plovdiv, Bulgaria January 2016 – May 2016

• PHP 5, MySQL, Git, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, HTML 5, CSS 3.

Extracurricular activity

Course Representative (1st and 2nd year)

University of Essex

• Representing and supporting students on the course and in the department.

Colchester, United Kingdom

October 2016 - June 2018

German 1 and 2

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom October 2016 – April 2018

Colchester, United Kingdom

July 2017 - September 2017

Colchester Zoo Volunteer

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom

April 2017

HackEssex 2017

University of Essex

- 24 hours hackathon.
- Eye tracking software integrated into a website.
- Selected as finalist for one of the top 3 best projects out of 20 competing.

UNESCO Project for an educational game

University of Essex

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

January 2015 - September 2016

- Main programmer.
- Project was made using the Unity Engine.